二零二四年安徽省中考英语听力录音。
一，短对话理解。
你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，请在每。
以小题所给的
B, Text 1 John, I heard you went to the art show.
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
How do you feel about it?
Fantastic! I really like the Chinese painting.
John, I heard you went to the art show.
How do you feel about it?
Fantastic! I really like the Chinese painting.
Text 2 What lovely weather it is!
Lying on the beach or swimming is a good idea.
Just lying on the beach is boring, and I don't like swimming.
Why not play volleyball?
That's great! What lovely weather it is!
Lying on the beach or swimming is a good idea.
lying on the beach is boring, and I don't like swimming.
Why not play volleyball?
That's great! Text 3 Tom, you look unhappy.
Anything wrong? I broke my mom's favorite glass when I was playing with the cat.
you look unhappy.
Anything wrong? broke my mom's favorite glass when I was playing with the cat.
Text 4 Excuse me, I've lost my student card.
Where can I get a new one?
You can get one at the service center.
It's behind the dining hall near the office building.
Excuse me, I've lost my student card.
Where can I get a new one?
You can get one at the service center.
It's behind the dining hall near the office building.
Text 5 Good evening.
May I take your order?
A moment please.
I'm still working on it.
Anything new on the menu?
Text 6 Good evening.
May I take your order?
A moment please.
I'm still working on it.
Anything new on the menu?
Text B, Text 6 A wonderful speech!
二，长对话理解。
你将听到两段对话，每段对话后有几个小题，请在。每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
每段对话读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答第六、七题
Have you ever made a public speech before?
Yes, I made my first speech last month.
Can you tell me more about it?
Sure. At first, I was a little excited.
But when I started, I became a little nervous, although I had practiced many times
the week before.
Slowly, I felt better and better.
I'm not surprised.
I was just like you when I made my first speech last year.
Text 8 A wonderful speech!
Have you ever made a public speech before?
Yes, I made my first speech last month.
Can you tell me more about it?
Sure. At first, I was a little excited.
But when I started, I became a little nervous, although I had practiced many times
the week before.
Slowly, I felt better and better.
I'm not surprised.
I was just like you when I made my first speech last year.
听下面一段对话，回答第八至十题。
Text 7 I'm reading a book about dreams these days.
What do you want to be in the future?
I want to be an actress.
What about you?
I wanted to be a doctor when I was at primary school, but now I want to be a writer.
Why? I find writing really makes me happy.
Sounds good, but it is not easy to become a writer.
I've tried, and some of my writings have come out in the local newspaper.
Cool! I hear there will be a writing competition next month.
Good news! I'll take part in it.
Hope you can win a prize.
Text I'm reading a book about dreams these days.
What do you want to be in the future?
I want to be an actress.
What about you?
I wanted to be a doctor when I was at primary school, but now I want to be a writer.
Why? I find writing really makes me happy.
Sounds good, but it is not easy to become a writer.
I've tried, and some of my writings have come out in the local newspaper.
Cool! I hear there will be a writing competition next month.
Good news! I'll take part in it.
Hope you can win text.
三，短文理解。
你。
将听到一篇短文，短文后有五个小题，请根据短文内容，在每小题所给的
三个选项中选出一个最佳选项。
Today is Father's Day.
I'm going to tell you something about my father.
He is a teacher and he is 40 years old.
In the morning, he usually gets up early and makes breakfast.
After breakfast, he drives me to school.
It takes us about 20 minutes.
Then he goes to work.
Late in the afternoon, he comes back home and cooks dinner together with my mother.
After dinner, my father helps me with my homework, especially math.
Because of him, I like math very much.
In the evening, we enjoy reading together for about 30 minutes.
He loves reading and I love reading too.
At the weekend, we usually go to the library.
My father loves music and I'm becoming interested in music too.
My father influences me a lot.
Thank you, Dad!
Happy Father's Day!
Today is Father's Day.
I'm going to tell you something about my father.
He is a teacher and he is 40 years old.
In the morning, he usually gets up early and makes breakfast.
After breakfast, he drives me to school.
It takes us about 20 minutes.
Then he goes to work.
Late in the afternoon, he comes back home and cooks dinner together with my mother.
After dinner, my father helps me with my homework, especially math.
Because of him, I like math very much.
In the evening, we enjoy reading together for about 30 minutes.
He loves reading and I love reading too.
At the weekend, we usually go to the library.
My father loves music and I'm becoming interested in music too.
My father influences me a lot.
Thank you, Dad!
Happy Father's Day!
四，信息转换。
You Sharing usually means enjoying something with others.
你将听到一篇短文，请根据短文内容写出下面表格中所缺的单词
每空仅填一词，短文读两遍。
It's important to learn how to share,
so let's take a look at the reasons.
helps us to make friends.
It helps others to feel cared about and shows that we are kind and friendly.
These are the things that we look for in a friend.
Secondly, sharing teaches us how to be fair.
You can't take all things just because you love them.
And you don't need to give up all things just because someone else wants them.
You should think about the needs of other people and your own.
Lastly, sharing gives us a sense of purpose.
It means doing something meaningful for others and makes us feel good about
ourselves. Sharing really is caring about others and ourselves.
Sharing usually means enjoying something with others.
It's important to learn how to share, so let's take a look at the reasons.
Firstly, sharing helps us to make friends.
It helps others to feel cared about and shows that we are kind and friendly.
These are the things that we look for in a friend.
Secondly, sharing teaches us how to be fair.
You can't take all things just because you love them.
And you don't need to give up all things just because someone else wants them.
You should think about the needs of other people and your own.
Lastly, sharing gives us a sense of purpose.
It means doing something meaningful for others and makes us feel good about
ourselves. Sharing really is caring about others and ourselves.
听力测试结束。